<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.2.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://shreeblog.in/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://shreeblog.in/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2021-08-31T11:49:09+05:30</updated><id>https://shreeblog.in/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Shridhar Wajapeya</title><subtitle>I am a freelance web/software developer. Please contact for any work and other queries.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">The start of my blogging journey.</title><link href="https://shreeblog.in/personal/2021/08/30/first-post/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The start of my blogging journey." /><published>2021-08-30T00:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2021-08-30T00:00:00+05:30</updated><id>https://shreeblog.in/personal/2021/08/30/first-post</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://shreeblog.in/personal/2021/08/30/first-post/">&lt;p&gt;I am 22 now, and I am over-concerned about sharing my ideas online. For me, social media has become a place to consume content, I never share anything. It’s unidirectional. I have incredibly low self-esteem. I don’t want to sound boring. Not only that, but I avoid posting online, thinking I don’t have good enough English.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But fuck it. I need to come out of this shell some day. Life will become too boring if I just keep my ideas and thoughts to myself. I have this illusion of people watching me all the time, which drives my anxiety. I have told myself that I will somehow ignore any bad and hurtful comments and focus on positive feedbacks and love people give me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My journey of programming and love with computers began 1.5 years back. It was the lowest time of my life, and I had lost myself. But programming has given me some kind of hope that some of my dreams may come true some day, if I keep working consistentl&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The reason to start this blog is to share my thoughts and ideas, but there is also the selfish motive of building audience and showcase my work. Programming is easy to begin with. It is exciting to watch your first ‘hello-world’ program to compile without any errors. But as you go on learning deep it becomes difficult. Programming asks for patience, consistency and constant learning. Have you heard the quote &lt;em&gt;the only constant is change&lt;/em&gt;? It applies perfectly to programming. It stirs my mind watching thousands of already existing cool tech and new tech coming out every day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;here-is-an-illustration&quot;&gt;here is an illustration&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/image/journey.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;programming journey graph&quot; title=&quot;programming journey graph&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Furthermore, it is mind-boggling to watch how far we have come in just some 8 decades. Though there were some important contributions to technology and science before the 20th century, but there wasn’t the kind of growth in technology what we saw in 20th century. The major catalyst for this kind of growth was the discovery of transistors, and then came the internet. It’s just so interesting to know how we make this piece of metal called processer do calculations and take instructions. And this processer is built with transistors with only two states,  on and off, and some place for storage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Have you come across the cool term called gen-z? The term is used to address the people born after 1996. It’s cool to be born at the intersection of two centuries. It’s cool that we played conventional physical games outdoors and had access to internet and smartphones just when our mind started opening up as we crossed teens. We are aware of how the life was before smartphone and cheap internet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am writing here without much filter. I share all kinds of stuff here in my blog that some people may find offending. Please understand that these are my personal opinions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I will be sharing my life experiences, programming tutorials and my observations in the field of technology and world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Subscribe to my blog so that you can get updates when I make new posts. And follow me on social media.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;links are at the bottom&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="personal" /><summary type="html">Why I want to start blogging and...</summary></entry></feed>